Now we're looking at the options for handling
our on-line orders. They're going through
the roof and frankly the lead-time for delivery
is blowing out. We need to improve our performance
in this area. Any suggestions?
Well, as I see it, we have three options.
The obvious one is to employ more people to
do the job. Another alternative is to automate
the system more - cut down on the physical
handling.
And the third option?
We could outsource.
What are the pros and cons?
Well, looking at increasing staff versus automation,
we have to consider the cost. Automating has
a higher capital cost than putting on more
staff. On the other hand, employing more people
is more expensive over a long term. If we
keep growing, it'll cost more in the long
run.
How likely is it that we'll see continued
growth?
I'd say it's a certainty.
I'd say a high probability. Nothing's certain
in business.
So what about the third option?
Outsourcing? Well, it does take the problem
off our hands. But we lose contact with our
customers.
What about the bottom line?
Outsourcing is the cheapest option, and the
easiest - in the short term. But if we want
to keep the operation in-house, the best option
is automating our system. The only down side
is, we're taking a risk that our business
will keep growing.
Which we hope it will.
We certainly do.
We've looked before at formal meetings. Today's
meeting is a more informal one, to discuss
a specific issue. The discussion is more free-flowing,
or uncontrolled. Let's look first at some
of the language used by Denise when she introduces
the problem.
Now we're looking at the options for handling
our on-line orders. They're going through
the roof and frankly the lead-time for delivery
is blowing out. We need to improve our performance
in this area.
Denise says, "We're looking at the options."
Options are different solutions, or answers,
to a problem. What is the problem? On-line
orders are going through the roof.
On-line orders are orders for goods received
through the internet, and if they're going
through the roof, they are increasing in number
very rapidly.
The lead-time for delivery is the amount of
time it takes from when the order is received
to when it's delivered, and if it's blowing
out - that time is becoming too long. We use
the expression blowing out for something which
is becoming too great, in a bad way.
So to improve our performance means, in this
case, to shorten the time it takes to deliver
goods.
Let's look at Tan's suggested options.
Well, as I see it, we have three options.
The obvious one is to employ more people to
do the job. Another alternative is to automate
the system more - cut down on the physical
handling.
And the third option?
We could outsource.
Tan describes three options. First he lets
us know that this is his opinion, by saying,
"As I see it."
Practise with Tan some different ways of letting
someone know that what you're stating is your
opinion.
As I see it, there are three options.
In my opinion there are three options.
From my point of view there are three options.
As far as I'm concerned, there are three options.
The three options are: employ more people,
automate, and outsource.
To outsource means to use an outside company.
When presenting different options, we can
order them by numbers, like this. Firstly,
we could employ more people, secondly we could
automate, and thirdly we could outsource.
We can also use phrases, such as 'one option
is to' and 'another option is to'.
We can also use linking words, such as 'or'
and 'alternatively'.
Or, we can use a combination of these methods.
Now let's look at the language used to discuss
these options.
Well, looking at increasing staff versus automation,
we have to consider the cost. Automating has
a higher capital cost than putting on more
staff. On the other hand, employing more people
is more expensive over a long term.
When considering two options, we are comparing
them. Barbara talks about increasing staff
versus automation. She is saying that she
is going to compare these two things. Another
phrase she could use is 'as against'. Practise
with her.
Let's look at increased staff versus automation.
Let's look at increased staff as against automation.
When comparing two things, we use comparative
adjectives.
Listen to Barbara again, and see if you can
hear the two comparative adjectives.
Automating has a higher capital cost than
putting on more staff. On the other hand,
employing more people is more expensive over
a long term.
She says automating has a higher capital cost
than putting on more staff. Higher is a comparative
adjective.
We often use 'than' for the option that is
being compared. Remember for words of longer
than two syllables, we use 'more' for the
comparative. Employing more people is more
expensive. Because Barbara has already said
what the second option is, automating, she
doesn't need to say employing more people
is more expensive than automating .
Notice that she uses the phrase 'on the other
hand'. This is used to introduce another side
to an argument. Practise this with Barbara.
On the one hand automation is expensive.
On the other hand it's more efficient.
Another way of comparing two ideas is to use
linking words such as but , although and however
.
Automation is expensive, but it's more efficient.
Although automation is expensive, it's more
efficient.
Automation is expensive, however it's more
Now listen to the discussion about the likelihood
of continued growth.
How likely is it that we'll see continued
growth?
I'd say it's a certainty.
I'd say a high probability. Nothing's certain
in business.
Denise asks how likely continued growth is.
In looking at words to describe likelihood,
we can use these words:
unlikely
possible
probable
certain
So we can say:
It's unlikely
It's possible
And so on.
We can also qualify these with words such
as: very, quite,
highly or reasonably
It' s very unlikely
It's quite possible
Its highly probable
It's reasonably certain
And in a different kind of sentence, we can
use them as nouns:
It's a certainty
It's a possibility
There's a probability
There's a high likelihood
But we don't say, "There's an unlikelihood."
We say, "There's no likelihood."
Finally, look at what happens when we compare
more than two options.
Outsourcing is the cheapest option, and the
easiest, in the short term. But if we want
to keep the operation in-house, the best option
is automating our system.
Did you hear the superlative adjectives used
to compare more than two things.
Listen again. There are three.
Outsourcing is the cheapest option, and the
easiest, in the short term. But if we want
to keep the operation in-house, the best option
is automating our system.
Well our bottom line is that that's all we
have time for today so I hope it's quite certain
I'll see you next time for The Business of
English.